ncu.edu 2014-10-28

# Privacy Statement and Consumer Information | Northcentral University

## Privacy Statement

Northcentral University is committed to protecting your privacy, developing technology that gives you a powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to Northcentrals websites, and governs data collection and use at all Northcentral sites and services. Please read the complete Statement of Privacy to learn additional details about how some of these sites and services protect your personal information.

**Collection of your Personal Information  
** At some sites, Northcentral University collects personally identifiable information, such as your email address, name, home or work addresses, or telephone numbers. At other sites, anonymous demographic information is collected that is not unique to you, such as ZIP Codes, age and gender. Some sites collect a combination of the two types of information.  
Northcentral automatically collects information about your computer hardware and software, as do other Internet entities. This information may include your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information serves to provide operational and statistical feedback.

**Use of your Personal Information** Northcentral University keeps track of visits to the Northcentral Web sites and pages in order to deliver customized content, and gauge the popularity and efficacy of sites, sections and services.

When you request information from Northcentral University, you are asked to provide contact information that is collected and used for the purpose of responding to your request. The contact information collected may include your name, address, home telephone number, mobile telephone number or email address. We may use this information to contact you through various means, including phone calls, text messages, e-mail and postal mail about the programs and services that we offer.

Northcentral does not sell, rent, lease or lend its lead, applicant, Student, or Mentor lists to third parties. Northcentral may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analyses. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information, except to provide such services to Northcentral, and are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Northcentral will not disclose your personal information, except as required to do so by law, or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Northcentral; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Northcentral; or (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Northcentral, its Web sites, or the public.  
Under the Federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974, a Students academic and financial files at Northcentral will not be released to any third party without the written consent of the Student.

**Use of Cookies and Web Beacons** A "cookie" is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a Web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page, which helps Northcentral recall your specific information on subsequent visits.

A "Web beacon" is typically a small transparent graphic image that works with cookies to count and recognize users, and track movement from point to point within a server network.

Northcentral Web sites use cookies to help you personalize your online experience. When you return to the same Northcentral Web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved so that you can easily use the features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Northcentral services or Web sites you visit.

**Control your Personal Information** Northcentral offers its Students choices for the collection, use and sharing of personal information. You may go to the Profile page to proactively make choices about the use and sharing of your personal information.

**Security of your Personal Information** Northcentral secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Northcentral University secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled environment protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites through the use of encrypted Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protection.

**Changes to this Statement  
** Northcentral may occasionally update this Statement of Privacy, and encourages you to periodically review this Statement to remain informed of how Northcentral is protecting your information.

## Consumer Information

Northcentral makes every effort to comply with federal, state and local laws and regulations. Here is a summary of our policies and procedures relating to a number of issues of concern to Students, Faculty Mentors and Northcentral staff.

Northcentral policies are subject to change. For additional information about our policies and procedures, see our current [Course Catalog](http://learners.ncu.edu/public_images/Northcentral%20University%20Catalog/Northcentral_University_Catalog.htm).

**Student Records** The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) protects the privacy of Student records.

**Legal and Regulatory Information**

  * Student Grievance Contact Information

**Americans With Disabilities Act** In accordance with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (ADA), the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 and subsequent regulations, Northcentral provides reasonable accommodation to a qualified individual with an appropriately documented disability, provided that such accommodation does not create an undue hardship.

**Web Accessibility Statement** The public Northcentral Web site is built to comply with Section 508 Accessibility Standards of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended in 1998.

**Disclosure of Campus Crime Statistics (Jeanne Clery Act)** Northcentral is not obligated to report Clery Act statistics as all courses are conducted online.

**Alcohol and Drug Policy** Northcentral is concerned about the use of alcohol, illegal drugs and controlled substances as it affects faculty, staff and Students.

**Sexual Harassment Policy** Northcentral policy prohibits sexual harassment between and among all members, Students, Faculty Mentors and staff of the Northcentral community in all areas of Northcentrals work and educational environments.

**Technical Requirements** Students, Mentors and even visitors to Northcentral will get the maximum benefit of their experiences by using adequate and compatible hardware and software.

Student Right-to-Know Graduation Rate Disclosure  The Student Right to Know (SRTK) Act, passed by Congress in 1990, requires all institutions eligible for Title IV funding to disclose graduation rates of degree- or certificate-seeking Students to all Students and prospective Students.

** Textbooks** Created in large part to help lower the prices students pay for textbooks, the Higher Education Opportunity Act (HEOA), went into effect July 1, 2010.

**Pledge of Public Accountability** The decision to attend an institution of higher education involves a significant financial commitment. At Northcentral University, we believe that any decision to do so should be supported by clear and accurate information.

**[Refund Policy and Procedure](http://learners.ncu.edu/public_images/Northcentral%20University%20Catalog/03_-_FINANCIAL_INFORMATION/3H_-_Refund_Policy_and_Procedure.htm)** Northcentral University's refund policy and procedures can be found in our current [catalog](http://learners.ncu.edu/public_images/Northcentral%20University%20Catalog/03_-_FINANCIAL_INFORMATION/3H_-_Refund_Policy_and_Procedure.htm).

**Program Disclosures** Northcentral University strives to enable students to make informed choices about their academic program selection by making disclosures to prospective Students in a clear, timely, and meaningful way.
